Jacob Namhyung Kim

Software Developer | Web Developer

Phone: +1-236-992-3397

Address: Vancouver, BC, Canada

Email: everywherejacobkim@gmail.com
LinkedIn & GitHub: /everywherejacobkim

Portfolio: devjacobkim.co

SUMMARY

Experienced web and mobile developer with a Post-Baccalaureate Diploma in web and mobile app development. Skilled in user-friendly web development using React and Next.js with TypeScript, as well as MERN stack. Experience with early-stage startups, building UI components and testing. Organizational and communication skills from previous role in technical support and program coordination. Passionate, self-motivated and focused on writing clean, secure code. Ready to contribute to team success.

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- TypeScript | JavaScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Node.js | Express.js
- React Native(app)
- Tailwind CSS
- GraphQL & Firebase
- Headless CMS
- MERN Stack
- CI/CD & Cypress

LANGUAGES & AWARDS

- English (Proficient)
- Korean (Native)
- Spanish (Intermediate)
- Dean's Honour Roll (Langara College | Spring, 2022)

TOOLS

GitHub, JIRA, Trello, Asana, Firebase, MongoDB Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

BuildN | Vancouver, BC | Oct 2023 - Feb 2024

- Developed a web platform for construction and renovation projects as a front-end developer in an early-stage startup.
- Optimized a production website into a mobile-responsive site using Next.js, Sass, and Material UI.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Homechow.ca | Vancouver, BC | Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

- Developed responsive UI components using Typescript and Next.js, ensuring optimal user experience across mobile and desktop platforms
- Utilized Cypress for debugging tests and managed UI components using Storybook

TECHNICAL SUPPORT & PROGRAM COORDINATOR

Consulate General of the Republic of Korea in Seattle | Seattle, USA | Jan 2015 – Dec 2020

- Supported and troubleshooted computer hardware, software, and networking issues to ensure optimal functioning of tech systems
- Organized and managed cultural and educational programs from conception to successful execution

EDUCATION

POST-DEGREE DIPLOMA: WEB AND MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT

Langara College | Vancouver | May 2021 – Dec 2022

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: EDUCATION TECHNOLOGY

Hanyang University | Seoul, South Korea | Mar 2009 - Feb 2014

PROJECTS (devjacobkim.com/projects)

- Handy Chef | Mobile App | React Native | Capstone Project
 Contributed as a front-end developer, leveraging React Native, to
 design and implement intuitive user interfaces for the Handy Chef
 mobile app, connecting independent chefs with clients for
 personalized dining experiences in their homes
- Pomodee | Web App | MERN | Langara College
 Played a key role as a front-end developer in building Pomodee, a web app based on the pomodoro tech, using React and MERN stack, enabling real-time collaboration and study/work sessions for users